A Register to the Raissa G. Zemmering Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Raissa G. Zemmering Papers
1933-1957
2008C53
Zemmering, Raissa Gavrilovna, 1892-1988.
1 microfilm reel 0.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence and miscellany, relating to the émigré Russian writer Ivan Shmelev. Mainly letters received from Ivan Shmelev.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by Hoover Institution Archives in 2008
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
The collection is available on microfilm
Location of Originals
In part, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers consist primarily of letters and postcards from Ivan Sergeevich Shmelev to Raissa Gavriilovna Zemmering. Most letters have been copied and typed by Raissa Zemmering after Shmelev's death. Included are also five letters from different individuals addressed to Raissa Zemmering. The Ivan Shmelev File include undated notes, and an undated typescript, "Ugodniki solovetskie."
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the online catalog.
Subjects
Russian literature.; Shmelev, I. S. (Ivan Sergeevich), 1873-1950.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1933-1957, and undated. (Box 1)
  Cards and letters from Ivan Shmelev and unidentified persons, arranged chronologically.
  - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1: 1)
  - Unidentified, 1951-1957 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Shmelev, Ivan Sergeevich
    - Undated (Folder 1: 3)
      (four letters)
    - 1933-1939 (Folder 1: 4)
    - 1940-1949 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1950 (Folder 1: 6)
- Ivan Shmelev File, 1949 and undated.
  Includes notes, power of attorney regarding publications, and typescript, arranged by physical form
  - Notes, undated (Folder 1: 7)
  - Power of attorney, 1949 (Folder 1: 8)
  - "Ugodniki solovetskie,", undated. (Folder 1: 9)
    Typescript
- Photographs, 1936-1950
  - One print of I. Shmelev (signed), 1941; one print of O. Shmeleva, 1936; and one print of Ivan Shmelev's apartment, 1950. (Folder 1: 10)
    Photographs are identified in Shmelev's handwriting